Prime, what we have here is an experimental all-terrain expeditionary fighting vehicle,
擎天柱 这是实验型全地形突击战车
designed by the finest engineers in our M.A.S.K. division.
由我们掩护部门最好的工程师们研制而成
Thank you, Agent Fowler.
谢谢你 福勒探员
This will most certainly do.
完全是为我量身定做的
Return trajectory fluctuations have been stabilized.
返回路径的波动已稳定
Ultra Magnus, we are ready to receive you.
通天晓 我们已准备好接你回来
We didn't find much else in the rubble of the former base.
我们对旧基地残骸的搜索没什么重大收获
You call this... "not much else?"
这个难道不算是“重大收获”？
Huh!
嘿！
Eh?
呃?
Wheeljack!
千斤顶！
You could've caused serious damage.
你这样可能会对他人造成严重伤害！
To me!
对我！
What in the Sam hill?
搞什么飞机呢？
A little help here?
帮把手行吗？
What were you thinking, soldier?
你头脑短路了么 士兵？
I was thinking Bulk would catch that lob.
我以为小隔能接住我那一球
Allow me to make myself clear.
我跟你把话说清楚！
As Optimus Prime's second-in-command,
作为擎天柱的首席副官
I have no intention of tolerating Wrecker behavior.
我绝不会纵容任何雷霆救援队式的作风
Some things never change.
有些人就是死心眼儿啊
Jackie...
老千…
Need I remind you that it was Optimus Prime himself who assigned me to command your Wreckers back on Cybertron
我提醒你 在塞博特恩 是擎天柱亲自任命我指挥你们雷霆救援队的
and get you loose cannons under control?
他让我来拴住你们这些脱缰野马！
An effective combat unit begins with discipline.
作为一名合格的战士 纪律永远是第一位的
If you won't accept that, feel free to choose the path of least resistance...
如果你无法做到这点 那么你大可以选择一条轻松的路
As you did before.
就如同你从前那样
If my ship weren't a twisted wreck at present,
要是我的飞船现在没变成一堆废铁
I'd do that... sir.
我早就拔腿走人了 长官…
Huh...
唉
So, any word from Optimus?
言归正传 有擎天柱的消息吗？
He's investigating recent Decepticon activity,
他正在调查霸天虎的近期活动
hopefully an Energon mine.
大有希望找到一个能量矿
Hmm...
嗯…
How rad would it be if you all had jetpacks like Optimus?
要是你们都有擎天柱的飞行背包 那该有多酷啊
Quite rad, Miko.
会很酷的 神子
But the Forge has been depleted of its power to do that.
但修复擎天柱已经耗尽了卓天越之锤的能量
Now it's only good for pounding out dings.
现在只能用它来敲东西了
Smokescreen?
烟幕?
Aw, what gave me away?
哇 你是怎么认出我的？
Come on, "robots in disguise," right?
给点支持嘛 伪装自己 不是吗？
Where have you been, soldier?
你去哪儿了 士兵？
Scanning new war paint.
去扫描新的战斗涂装
Thought it'd be proactive to follow Optimus' lead...
我觉得自己该主动向擎天柱学习…
and Bumblebee's.
还有大黄蜂
Now you can look your best while stacking those empty cubes.
现在你可以衣着光鲜地去堆那些空箱子了
Yes, sir.
遵命 长官
I was nearly a Prime, but somehow I'm still a rookie.
我差点都当领袖了 却还把我当成菜鸟
What was that about a "Prime?"
你说什么“领袖”？
Uh... no, time.
呃…不 是“领悟”
Time to stop acting like a rookie.
我该领悟到 自己不能再当菜鸟了
Smokescreen was the only one who went back.
烟幕是唯一一个回去救擎天柱的人
If it weren't for him,
如果没有他
Optimus might not be with us today.
擎天柱可能已经离开我们了
Arcee, we were under the strictest of orders.
阿尔茜 我们当时接到了死命令
The three of you had your human partners to protect.
你们三个必须保护你们的人类伙伴
But we are fortunate that Smokescreen is inexperienced enough not to have followed protocol.
但幸运的是 烟幕严重缺乏实战经验 没有服从命令
There. I can see it.
在那里 我看到了
Abandon the excavation.
停止挖掘！
Now.
立刻！
Attack!
给我打！
Optimus, did you find Energon?
擎天柱 你找到能量了？
No. But I did uncover this.
没有 但是我发现了这个
It cannot be.
这不可能是…
Be what?
是什么？
The ancient remains...
一块儿古老的…
of a Predacon.
…巨狰狞遗骸
Though it remains unclear why such a skull would be found on your planet,
就算这块头骨出现在你们星球的原因尚不明朗
its presence reveals all too much about the Predacon which Megatron recently sent in pursuit of us.
但它的出现一定和威震天 最近派出追击我们的巨狰狞紧密相关
You mean that dragon bot we put on ice?
你是说那只被我们冻住的机器龙？
Except that Predacons have been extinct since, well...
但巨狰狞早已灭绝了 早在…早在…
Since before most life began on Cybertron.
早在大多数生命出现在塞博特恩之前
They're like Earth's dinosaurs.
他们就像是地球上的恐龙
Which means, for you guys, running into one would be like us meeting a T-Rex.
就是说 你们见到巨狰狞就好比我们碰到霸王龙一样
So then what were dinobots?
那机器恐龙呢？
Totally different.
完全不是一码事
With Megatron's seeming new interest in the excavation of prehistoric skeletons
看来挖掘远古遗骸已成了威震天的新兴趣
and a certain scientist back among the Decepticon ranks...
再加上霸天虎队伍里的那个科学家…
It would stand to reason
由此推断
that Shockwave cloned the beast from one such find.
震荡波根据这种遗骸克隆出了那只野兽
And now Megatron's looking to clone another.
而现在威震天想再克隆一只
What makes you think buckethead would stop at just one?
你觉得铁桶头会仅仅满足于一只么？
We could have beast wars on our hands.
我们将会面临一场野兽之战
And if Shockwave only requires a single strand of CNA
而且 如果震荡波仅凭一小股C.N.A.
from which to clone a beast...
就可以克隆出一只野兽的话…
He already possesses what he needs to engender this one.
那么他已经得到克隆它所需的一切了
Autobots, we must become Beast Hunters.
汽车人们 我们必须得化身为野兽猎人了
One thing still doesn't follow.
还有一件事仍然说不通
Predacons went extinct on Cybertron.
既然巨狰狞在塞博特恩就已经灭绝了
So what would their bones be doing here?
他们的骸骨怎么会出现在这里？
On Earth?
在地球上？
I mean, isn't it just a little preposterous?
你们不觉得这有点荒谬吗？
They are not the remains of Predacons, Starscream.
这些骸骨并非属于巨狰狞 红蜘蛛
But, rather, the remains of Predacon clones.
它们来自于巨狰狞的克隆体
For you see... Our recent Autobot hunter wasn't the first bestial super-soldier
你还不知道 我们最近释放的这只汽车人猎手
Shockwave ever attempted to breed from prehistoric matter.
并不是震荡波从史前遗骸中 培育出的第一个超级野兽战士
During the war for Cybertron,
早在塞博特恩战争时期
I sanctioned the dispatch of a small army of these preda-clones to Earth
我就授权将一小支巨狰狞克隆体部队派到了地球
to unleash the beasts on unwitting Autobot forces stationed here.
用以消灭毫无防备的汽车人地球驻守部队
Once they accomplished their mission,
当它们完成了任务
the surviving Predacons held sentinel on this very world
幸存的巨狰狞克隆体留在了这个世界
for ages to come,
在未来的岁月里作为我忠诚的哨兵
guarding the Energon reserves they had managed to secure
看守着它们夺取的能量储备
while awaiting my arrival.
并等待着我的到来
Of course, our reunion here was much delayed,
当然 我们的重聚被延误了很久
and it would seem we lost the beasts to the ravages of time.
而且 看起来我们的野兽没有经受住时间的考验
But not their endo-matter,
但其内部物质却得以幸存
from which I am logically able to extract their very CNA.
逻辑上我可以由此提取出他们的C.N.A.
Pff. Another scavenger hunt?
切…又要我们去捡破烂？
How logical would it really be to locate all the dusty remains of your former pets?
逻辑上 我们要在如此广大的世界里 寻找你旧宠物那些老得掉渣的…残骸
You are not suggesting that I would send my creations to a distant planet
你觉得我将自己的创造物 派往一个遥远的星球之前
without first having them... micro-chipped?
不会先给他们装上定位芯片吗？
Eh... Well... well, I was.
呃…我本来是这么觉得的
But, seriously, you did?
不过 说真的 你真装上了？
From our historical texts.
这是我们历史文献中的资料
But those are metal versions of creatures from our Greek mythology and medieval literature.
但这些几乎都是我们的神话和中世纪文学中 所描述的生物 只不过换成了金属版本
Not dinosaurs.
根本不是恐龙
It would stand to reason that Predacons did indeed walk upon this Earth in ancient times,
巨狰狞在古代曾经出没于地球 应该是一个合理的推断
as they seem to have been the basis for much of humankind's folklore.
因为它们似乎已成为众多人类民间传说的重要组成部分
Illustrating once again that the pasts of Earth and Cybertron are inextricably linked.
这再次证明了地球与塞博特恩的过去是紧密相连的
Synthetic Energon?
人工合成能量？
Indeed.
没错
I am concerned that without access to any Energon reserves since our base was destroyed,
鉴于我们的基地被毁 我们失去了所有的能量储备
our ability to deal with impending crises will be severely hampered.
我担心我们应对危机的能力会被严重削弱
A wise decision, old friend.
一个明智的决定 老朋友
Just, please...
但是 请你…
manage your expectations.
别抱太高期望
I am working with even more rudimentary hardware than before.
毕竟我的工作环境比从前还要简陋
Prime! Satellite surveillance has picked up two signs of Decepticon activity:
擎天柱 卫星监控侦测到了两处霸天虎的活动迹象
one near an oil field outside of El Paso,
一处靠近埃尔帕索油田
the other near the Hebrides bluffs in Scotland.
另一处在苏格兰赫布里底群岛峭壁附近
So don't Forget to pack your kilts.
所以别忘了带上苏格兰短裙
We must divide our resources.
我们必须兵分两路
Ultra Magnus, lead the Wreckers to the bluffs.
通天晓 你带领雷霆救援队员前往峭壁
Yes, Optimus.
遵命 擎天柱
Uh... What's a kilt?
呃…苏格兰短裙是什么?
Agent Fowler can, at times, be oblique.
福勒探员有时候说话不太着调
I find it best to simply nod and mobilize.
我觉得这种时候我们最好无视他 然后尽快离开
Bulkhead, Wheeljack, let's roll.
隔板 千斤顶 跟我出发！
Uh...
唉…
Optimus, I know there are many emotions tied to the Forge.
擎天柱 我知道这把铸锤身上寄托了很多的情感
This is no time to stand on ceremony.
现在没有时间来缅怀这些了
I would be honored to put this to some practical use.
我很荣幸能去发挥它的实战价值
I will search this quadrant.
我去搜索这个区域
Hey 'Bee,
嘿 小蜂
have you ever thought you might wanna be a Prime?
你想没想过你或许会成为一名领袖？
Not now. Someday.
当然不是现在 在将来的某天
"Warrior." Yeah, you and me both.
你是战士 没错 这点咱俩一样
But I've seen you in action,
但我见过你的能耐
Optimus knows you can scrap with the best of 'em.
擎天柱知道你是打虎能手
Why won't he just promote you from scout already?
为什么他还要你当侦察兵 而不晋升你？
Your choice? Hmm.
你自愿的？好吧
So, why wait?
为什么甘于做个小兵
Guess it would be more meaningful to graduate back home on Cybertron.
我猜将晋升的那一刻 留给回到塞博特恩确实更有意义
You're one patient guy.
你是个耐得住性子的人
I should take a cue.
我该向你学学
Like I said, you got nice chops for a scout.
我就说吧 你作为一个侦察兵真是屈才了
How epic was that?
这一幕够经典！
Whoo! And that's why he's a Prime!
哇哦…这就是为什么他才是领袖！
Soundwave.
声波
Enough.
够了！
No!
不！
We have all that we need.
我们已经拿到所需要的全部了！
"A single strand of CNA..."
一小股C.N.A.
Shockwave.
震荡波
I understand that you engaged Optimus Prime in the field.
我了解到你在战场上与擎天柱正面交锋了
Only in order to secure the specimen, lord Megatron.
仅仅是为了保全这个样本 威震天陛下
I believed that you had perished once,
我最欣赏的工程师啊
my most prized engineer,
我已经失去过你一次了
and I highly doubt that project Predacon can be completed without you.
而且我极度怀疑 如果没有你 巨狰狞计划还能否完成
I shall leave the fetching of bones to Starscream,
我会将取回遗骸的任务转交给红蜘蛛
and confine myself to my laboratory in order to accelerate results.
而我本人则会留在实验室里 以加快计划的完成速度
Excellent...
非常好！
For I am rather impatient
因为我已经迫不及待
to witness my army of beasts trample humankind underfoot.
想要欣赏我的野兽大军将人类踏在脚下的美景了